ibanet.org 2018-07-11

# IBA - Privacy policy

##  1. Introduction

This Privacy Notice sets out the data processing practices carried out by the International Bar Association.

If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices, please contact [dataprotection@int-bar.org](mailto:dataprotection@int-bar.org?subject=Data%20Protection%20query). Please note that all data thus captured will be used and held in accordance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and the resulting Data Protection Act 2018.

Back to top

* * *

##  2. Who We Are

The International Bar Association, established in 1947, is the world's leading organisation of international legal practitioners, bar associations and law societies. The IBA influences the development of international law reform and shapes the future of the legal profession throughout the world. It has a membership of more than 80,000 individual lawyers and more than 190 bar associations and law societies spanning over 170 countries. It has considerable expertise in providing assistance to the global legal community.

International Bar Association is incorporated as a Not-for-Profit Corporation under the laws of the State of New York in the United States of America and is registered with the Department of State of the State of New York with registration number 071114000655 - and the liability of its members is limited. Its registered address in New York is c/o Capitol Services Inc, 1218 Central Avenue, Suite 100, Albany, New York 12205.

The London office of International Bar Association is registered in England and Wales as a branch with registration number FC028342.

The International Bar Associations Human Rights Institute Trust is also a registered charity no. 1133427. The International Bar Associations Human Rights Institute Trust has been created to advance education in the law throughout the world for the benefit of the public; to promote research into commonly encountered legal problems and to disseminate the useful results of such research for the benefit of the public; to promote human rights throughout the world; to promote the relief of financial hardship or distress of lawyers, their widows, widowers and other dependants and employees

Each of these organisations are data controllers under the data protection rules.

Back to top

* * *

##  3. Information collection

##  3.1 Ways we collect data

We collect information in the following ways:

  1. **Information you give us**. For example, when you engage with us by registering for an event, becoming a member or otherwise provide us with personal information. When you register, we’ll ask for personal information, like your name, email address and telephone number to store with your account.
  2. **Information we get from your use of our website and services**. We collect information about the services you use and how you use them, like when you visit our websites or view and interact with our content.
  3. **Information from third parties**. We may also receive information about you from third parties. This can include information such as your name, postal address, email address, phone number, your geographic location (for mobile devices), credit/debit card details. We, like all companies, are able to confirm what browser you are using, IP address and computer operating systems that are being used and this information may be used to improve the services we offer.
  4. **Information from Research**. We may also obtain information about you from your company website and other public sources such as LinkedIn. We will notify you when we receive your data and you will be given the opportunity to opt out of all communication and to remove your data immediately.

##  3.2 Sensitive Personal Data

Data Protection law recognises that certain categories of personal information are more sensitive. This is known as sensitive personal data and covers health information, race, religious beliefs and political opinions. We do not usually collect sensitive personal data about you unless there is a clear reason for doing so, such as any dietary requirements when attending a conference (which may infer religious beliefs) or where we need this information to ensure that we provide appropriate facilities or support to enable you to participate in an event.

Back to top

* * *

##  4. Use of personal information

We process personal information collected via this website for the purposes of:

  1. providing and personalising our services
  2. dealing with your inquiries and requests
  3. administering orders and accounts relating to our suppliers or members/delegates/purchasers;
  4. administering membership records;
  5. providing you with information about products and services.
  6. providing membership and Conference registration services
  7. exchanging personal information with third parties e.g. Sponsors, Exhibitors, Mailing Houses, e-mail marketing software providers, Marketing and Telesales.
  8. Fundraising for the IBA Human Rights Institute
  9. Maintaining information as a reference tool or general resource.
  10. Carrying out market research campaigns.
  11. General administration for the benefit of the association and its members.
  12. Google Analytics to measure the use of the website (see Cookies).
  13. F5 Security systems – this is a cloud based security service that collects traffic via proxies in datacentres around the planet. It checks all web traffic and cleans it for any threats such as viruses, trojans or data scraping based on rules, known vulnerabilities and poor reputation of the device being used to access our site. This then passes all the cleaned requests onwards to our Web server.

Back to top

* * *

##  5. Website users

All IBA websites use cookies to help our websites work well and to track information about how people are using them. More information on cookies can be found in section 5.1 - see Cookies.

In addition, if you register on our websites then the following will also apply:

  1. All IBA websites collect personal information when you register with us.
  2. The website you sign up to will collect information such as your name, email address and post code. Once you register with that website you will not be anonymous to us when you subsequently sign in.
  3. As part of the registration process and continued use of IBA services, you agree that any registration information you give to IBA will always be accurate, correct and up to date. Should you need to amend any of your personal information, you can do so by logging into My IBA or by getting in touch with the Membership Services Team on +44 (0) 20 7842 0090 or [member@int-bar.org](mailto:member@int-bar.org).
  4. We collect and retain information about your interactions with us so that we can process your interactions and deal with future queries.
  5. We use cookies to allow us to store limited information on an individual’s computer to either track them through tracking cookies or to allow people to have automatic logons as an example. We use this information to provide you with a good experience when browsing our website and to improve the functionality of our site.

Parts of the IBA website are restricted to IBA members only.

##  5.1 IBA Cookies

To provide the best experience to our users the IBA makes use of cookies. Our cookies do not store sensitive personal information. They only store the browser association that loads the data and provides a dynamic experience for the site user.  
The full policy can be found at What are cookies and how are they used?

Domain |  Cookie |  What it is used for  
---|---|---  
www.ibanet.org |  __utma,  
__utmb,  
__utmc,  
__utmt,  
__utmv,  
__utmz,  
_ga |  These cookies provide general analytics information tracking user experience.  
www.ibanet.org |  ASP.NET_SessionId,  
TS015eaf6b |  General storage about,the site user to enhance the site experience. When logged in this stores,server side information that further enhances the site experience.  
For, example pre-populating forms and details.  
www.int-bar.org |  CFID,  
CFTOKEN,  
TS011224ec |  General storage about,the site user to enhance the site experience. When logged in this stores,server side information that further enhances the site experience.  
For, example pre-populating forms and details.  
  
##  5.2 Third Party cookies

When on the International Bar Association Web site, you may notice some cookies are not related to our domain. Third party plug in technology helps to make a better and more dynamic experience when using the IBA web site. The third party cookies these companies use are listed overleaf.

Company |  Domain |  Cookie |  What it is used for  
---|---|---|---  
Cloudflare |  .cloudflare.com |  __cfduid |  Cloudflare is used for fonts on the IBA website. Tracking information to assist in this is used in the cookie.  
Twitter |  cdn.syndication.twimg.com |  lang |  Cookie to store local language to assist content loading.  
Twitter |  .twitter.com |  _ga,  
eu_cn,  
guest_id,  
mobile_metrics_token,  
netpu,  
personalization_id,  
syndication_guest_id,  
tfw_exp,  
twitter_ads_id |  Used to assist in the dynamic experience of twitter alongside general analytics information tracking user experience.  
Twitter |  syndication.twitter.com |  lang |  Cookie to store local language to assist content loading.  
Vimeo |  .vimeo.com |  __qca,  
_ga,  
continuous_play_v3,  
has_logged_in,  
is_logged_in,  
player,  
vuid |  These cookies help Vimeo player run and work from inside the IBA Web site.  
Vimeo |  .player.vimeo.com |  __utma,  
__utmb,  
__utmc,  
__utmt_player,  
__utmv,  
__utmz |  These cookies provide general analytics information tracking user experience.  
  
##  5.3 Third Party cookies from sites containing IBA advertising

We utilise the technology of third parties on a regular basis to ensure that we are using up to date systems that are managed by the best companies to provide us with the information that we need. This in turn means that there will be a number of third party cookies from our trusted suppliers used on our websites. Each company is responsible for the cookies that they place onto your device and have separate policy documents to highlight their use.

Our list of trusted third parties who may deploy a cookie to your device, with a link to their cookie details is below.

If you click on links through to their sites, you are then covered by their Privacy Policy and not ours.

##  5.4 Inappropriate website content

If you post or send any content that we believe to be inappropriate, offensive or in breach of any laws, such as defamatory content on our forums or social media pages, we may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your internet provider or law enforcement agencies.

Back to top

* * *

##  6. Your debit and credit card information

If you use your credit or debit card to join us, buy something or pay for a registration online or over the phone, we will ensure that this is done securely and in accordance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. You can find our more information about PCI DSS here -  
We do not store your credit or debit card details at all as all transactions are made through Secure Trading or WorldPay, depending on the method of payment.

If we receive an email containing any credit or debit card details, it will be immediately deleted, no payment will be taken and you will be notified about this. All purchases should be completed through the IBA website or by sending payment via bank transfer.

Back to top

* * *

##  7. Legal basis for processing personal data

In most instances, we collect and use your personal information by relying on the legitimate interest legal basis. This is because when you, for example, request to receive services or products from the IBA, we have a legitimate organisational interest to use your personal information to respond to you and there is no overriding prejudice to you by using your personal information for this purpose. This is also the case where we process your donations in support of IBAHRI and the IBA Foundation's objectives, for our internal administrative purposes, and where we need to take steps to protect our network security or risk of fraud.

In some instances, we will rely on obtaining your consent to our use of your personal information. This is the case, for example, where we seek to obtain your consent to receive email marketing about the IBA.

Back to top

* * *

##  8. Marketing – It’s your choice

We want to ensure you receive the level of information about the IBA that is right for you. It is always your choice as to whether you want to receive information about our work and the ways you can get involved. If you do not want us to use your personal information in these ways please indicate your preferences on the form on which we collect your data, in the MyIBA Manage Preferences option or contact us at [member@int-bar.org](mailto:member@int-bar.org). You will always receive communication about your account and membership renewal.

You may opt-out of our marketing communications at any time by clicking the ‘Opt-out/unsubscribe’ link in at the end of our marketing emails. You can also change any of your contact preferences at any time (including telling us that you don’t want us to contact you for marketing purposes by telephone, or by post) by contacting our Membership Services Team on +44 (0) 20 7842 0090 or [member@int-bar.org](mailto:member@int-bar.org). If you do opt out, we will retain your details on a suppression list to help ensure that we do not continue to contact you.

##  8.1 Email Marketing

If you actively provide your consent to us along with your email address, we will contact you for marketing purposes by email. By subscribing to IBA emails or opting in to email communication from IBA, you grant us the right to use the email for both email marketing purposes and advertisement targeting.

##  8.2 Post/telephone marketing

If you have provided us with your postal address or telephone number we may send you direct mail or telephone you about our work unless you have told us that you would prefer not to receive such information.

##  8.3 IBA Members’ Directory

One of the benefits of membership is that you can be listed in the IBA Members’ Directory. If you would like to opt out of appearing, choose ‘Manage Profile’ from the My IBA Home menu, and select ‘Yes’ or ‘No’ under ‘Make your Profile Public’ to make your profile accessible or inaccessible through ‘Members Directory’. Note that only current Members, Group Members, and Corporate Members have access to the Members’ Directory.

##  8.4 Photography and Filming

Certain sessions and/or social functions may be photographed and/or filmed and some of this content may be used for future IBA marketing materials, member communications, products or services. Should you have any concerns with regard to this, or do not wish to be featured in any of these materials please contact the IBA Marketing Department at [ibamarketing@int-bar.org](mailto:ibamarketing@int-bar.org).

Back to top

* * *

##  9. Data Retention

In order to comply with accounting regulations, we keep records for all individuals who have purchased goods or services from the IBA (e.g. conference registration, IBA membership) for 7 years, and will continue to send you marketing information about related conferences or about IBA membership during that period.

If you register your interest for a conference, but have not yet attended one, we retain your contact details for up to 3 years and will send you marketing information about related conferences or about IBA membership.

If you applied for membership but never completed your application, we will leave the invoice available to you until the end of the calendar year. We would then suspend your membership and keep your record for up to 3 years after that; we will continue to send you marketing information about related conferences or about IBA membership.

You can opt out at any time by emailing [member@int-bar.org](mailto:member@int-bar.org) or logging into your My IBA and going to Manage Preferences.

Back to top

* * *

##  10\.  Your rights to your personal information

Under the Data Protection Act 2018, you have the following rights:

**1\. The right to be informed** \- this is fulfilled through this notice.

**2\. The right of access -** you have the right to obtain confirmation that your data is being processed and access to your personal data. This is so that you are aware of and can verify the lawfulness of the processing. If you request the information, we will provide a copy of the information free of charge. However, we will charge a ‘reasonable fee’ when a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if it is repetitive. This also applies to additional copies of the same information. The information will be provided without excessive delay, and at the latest within one month of receipt. This period can be extended by a further two months where requests are complex or numerous. If this is the case, we will inform you within one month of the receipt of the request and explain why the extension is necessary. The information will be sent as a password-protected PDF. Where requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, in particular because they are repetitive, we may charge a reasonable fee taking into account the administrative costs of providing the information; or refuse to respond. Where we refuse to respond to a request, we will explain why to you, informing you of your right to complain to the supervisory authority and to a judicial remedy without undue delay and at the latest within one month.

Should you wish to exercise these rights, we require you to prove your identity with two pieces of approved identification. Please address requests to the Operations Director, International Bar Association, 10 St Bride St, London, EC4A 4AD and we will respond within 30 days, of receipt of your written request and confirmed ID. Please provide as much information as possible about the nature of your contact with us to help us locate your records.

Further information can be found in our Data Subject Access Request policy and form.

**3\. The right to rectification** \- to amend your personal information log in to MyIBA, choose ‘Manage Personal Details’, where you can amend all your personal data. If you are unable to log in to MyIBA, it may mean that your membership status does not grant you access to members’ area of the website. If you need to inquire about your level of access or if you wish to remove your data, please contact the Membership Services Team, [member@int-bar.org](mailto:member@int-bar.org), and they will assist you.

If we have disclosed the personal data in question to third parties, we will inform them of the rectification where possible. We can also inform you about the third parties to whom the data has been disclosed where appropriate.

**4\. The right to erase** \- this is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’. The broad principle underpinning this right is to enable you to request the deletion or removal of personal data where there is no compelling reason for its continued processing. If you would like us to erase you from our database, please email [member@int-bar.org](mailto:member@int-bar.org). If we have disclosed the personal data in question to third parties, we will inform them about the erasure of the personal data, unless it is impossible or involves disproportionate effort to do so.

**5\. The right to restrict processing** \- individuals have a right to ‘block’ or suppress processing of personal data. When processing is restricted, we are permitted to store the personal data, but not further process it. We are able to retain just enough information about the individual to ensure that the restriction is respected in future e.g. your name and email address on an email marketing suppression list. 

The right to restrict processing applies in the following circumstances:

  * Where you contest the accuracy of the personal data, we will restrict the processing until we have verified the accuracy of the personal data.
  * Where you have objected to the processing (where it was necessary for the purpose of legitimate interests), and we are considering whether our legitimate grounds override yours.
  * When processing is unlawful and you oppose erasure and request restriction instead.
  * If we no longer need the personal data but you require the data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.

If we have disclosed the personal data in question to third parties, we will inform them about the restriction on the processing of the personal data, unless it is impossible or involves disproportionate effort to do so. We will inform you if we decide to lift a restriction on processing.

**6\. The right to object - y** ou have the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests (including profiling) and direct marketing (including profiling). The objection must be on “grounds relating to his or her particular situation”. We will inform you of your right to object in the first communication you receive from us. We will stop processing personal data for direct marketing purposes as soon as we receive an objection.

**7.** **The right to data portability** \- you have the right to obtain the data that the IBA processes on you and use it for your own purposes. This means you have the right to receive the personal data that you have provided to the IBA in a structured machine readable format and to transmit the data to a different data controller. 

This right applies in the following circumstances:

  * where you have provided the data to the IBA
  * where the processing is carried out because you have given the IBA your consent to do so
  * where the processing is carried out in order to perform the employment contract between you and the IBA
  * where processing is carried out by automated means. No membership data is processed using automated means so this right does not apply. 

Back to top

* * *

##  11. Rights in relation to profiling and remarketing

##  11.1 Profiling

We may collect, and our third party providers of advertisements and content may collect, information about where you are on the internet (e.g. the URL you came from, IP address, domain types like .co.uk and .com), your browser type, the country and telephone area code where your computer is located, purchase history, the pages of our website that were viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms that you entered on our website ("User Information"). We may collect this information even if you do not register with us.

You should be aware that this site is being monitored and may capture information about your visit that will help us improve the quality of our service, or be used to present you with IBA products and services which are relevant to your browsing history when you visit other websites.

##  11.2 Remarketing

The IBA uses remarketing on other websites to present you with products and services we think may be of interest to you, based on your browsing history. Third-party vendors, including Google, Facebook, Linkedin and Twitter, may show IBA adverts on sites across the Internet.

We do have relationships with carefully-selected and monitored suppliers who may also set cookies during your visit to be used for remarketing purposes, to show you different products and services based on what you appear to be interested in. These companies also use automated technologies to collect information when you click on our ads, which helps track and manage the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. If you'd like to opt out, please go to the Network Advertising Initiative website (opens in a new window - please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites).

Back to top

* * *

##  12. Recipients – Information and Disclosure

The IBA may disclose your personal information in the following circumstances:

  1. To suppliers or service providers only to provide the products or services you've requested from us where, for example, we use a separate company to deliver goods to you.
  2. To third parties who provide a service to us and are data processors. This would include our trusted partners that work with us, and other entities that act as fundraisers for IBA, sell IBA products or provide IBA information and marketing (subject to your communication preferences and our internal policies and procedures). We require these third parties to comply strictly with our instructions and data protection laws and we will make sure that appropriate controls are in place. We enter into contracts with all of our data processors and regularly monitor their activities to ensure they are complying with IBA policies and procedures.
  3. Where we are under a duty to disclose your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation (for example, to government bodies and law enforcement agencies), or in order to enforce or apply our rights (including in relation to our website or other applicable terms and conditions) or to protect the IBA, for example in cases of suspected fraud or defamation.
  4. To IBA Officers, to assist with the running of the IBA.

Back to top

* * *

##  13. International transfers of personal information

As the IBA is a global association, we have regional offices in Sao Paulo, Seoul and Washington, They transfer, process and store the data hosted in the EU in order to provide IBA services at a more local level. If they use any data regarding European Economic Area (EEA) citizens, they sign a data sharing agreement.

We also use suppliers (such as conference venues) outside the EEA. This means that your personal information is transferred, processed and stored outside the EEA. This includes countries that the European Union authorities do not consider provides and adequate level of protection for personal data. However, we take steps to put in place suitable safeguards to protect your personal information when processed by the supplier such as entering into the European Commission approved standard contractual clauses. If you would like to receive further information about our safeguards, please contact [dataprotection@int-bar.org](mailto:dataprotection@int-bar.org)

Back to top

* * *

##  14. Changes to this privacy policy

We may update the terms of this policy at any time, so please do check it from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address you have provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our website(s). By continuing to use our website, you will be deemed to have accepted such changes.

Back to top

* * *

##  15. Complaints, compliments or comments

If you are unhappy with our work or something that we have done or failed to do, we want to know about it. We also welcome your views on what we do well. Your comments enable us as an organisation to learn and continuously improve our services. Email us at [dataprotection@int-bar.org](mailto:dataprotection@int-bar.org) or our Operations Director, at [joe.bell@int-bar.org](mailto:joe.bell@int-bar.org)

If you are still not satisfied after you have spoken to us, you can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office - [www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)

Back to top

* * *
